Guide to the Robert L. Bracklow Photograph Collection 1882-1918 (bulk, 1896-1905) PR 8
New-York Historical Society
- Series II: Trappan Gift: Photograph Albums, 2
  - Subseries II.23: "May Days in Berkshires" [Album 21], 23
    - Memorial Day Parade [Great Barrington (Mass.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
      Same image as Alland # 896
    - A Bit of Pasture, Mr. Addams' farm [Great Barrington (Mass.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
    - Apple tree near barn on Mr. A. D. Davis' farm [Great Barrington (Mass.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
    - A bit of road near Mr. A.D. Davis' farm [Lenox (Mass.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
    - Apple Blossoms [Lenox (Mass.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
    - Shady side-walk, Kernble Street [Lenox (Mass.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
    - Episcopal Church, Kernble Street [Lenox (Mass.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
    - Episcopal Church, Walker and Kernble Streets [Lenox (Mass.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
    - Monument to Gen. Patterson and Major Eggleston [Lenox (Mass.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
    - Old Town Hall, now Public Library [Lenox (Mass.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
    - Congregational Church on the hill [Lenox (Mass.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
    - Hawthorne Pines [Stockbridge (Mass.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
    - Lake Mahkeenac, or Stockbridge Bowl [Stockbridge (Mass.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
    - Main St. looking south [Great Barrington (Mass.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
    - Main St. looking north [Great Barrington (Mass.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
    - Housatonic River near High School [Housatonic River (Mass. and Conn.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
    - Great Barrington from Quarry Street, looking west [Great Barrington (Mass.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
    - Great Barrington looking northwest from Quarry Street [Great Barrington (Mass.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
    - Monument Mountain from near Quarry [Great Barrington (Mass.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
    - Picturesque bit, Quarry Street [Great Barrington (Mass.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
    - Housatonic River, near cemetery [Housatonic River (Mass. and Conn.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
    - Congregational Church and parsonage [Great Barrington (Mass.)], 1905 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 22)
  - Subseries II.24: "Harper's Ferry" [Album 22], 24
    - on the road [Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
      Bottom image.
    - The old "Williams Property" on the Shenandoah [Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
      Top image.
    - [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - An old homestead, on the Shenandoah [Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - Bridge on the valley branch of the "B. & O." on the Shenandoah [Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - Spring time on the Shenandoah [Shenandoah River (Va. and W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - Spring time on the Shenandoah [Shenandoah River (Va. and W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
      Left image.
    - [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
      Right image.
    - St. Peter's R.C. Church [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - [Shenandoah River (Va. and W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - [Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - Looking up High Street, from Shenandoah Street [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - Looking down High Street [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - Did you take our picture? [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - Jefferson Rock, above the Shenandoah [Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - Looking down the Potomac River [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - Lining up the boys for their picture [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
      Bottom middle image.
    - St. Peter's R. C. Church - interior [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - Harper's Ferry from the B. & O. R. R. [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - Sunday morning gossip [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - The Potomac River [Potomac River], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - On the Potomac, looking toward Harper's Ferry [Potomac River], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - [Potomac River Valley], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - In the Glen [Potomac River Valley], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - Washington Street [Bolivar (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - Cherry Tree in bloom, Camp Hill [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - Cottage in the hollow, upper High St. [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - Weverton, at the junction [Weverton (Md.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - Portrait [], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - Portrait [], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
    - A couple [], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 28, Album 23)
  - Subseries II.25: "Harper's Ferry" [Album 23], 25
    - On Shenandoah Street, Harper's Ferry [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 24)
    - Old tree and bridge. Ruin of cotton mill [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 24)
    - Ruins on the Shenandoah [Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 24)
    - Looking across the Shenandoah, where some fo the killed of John Brown's men were buried [Shenandoah River (Va. and W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 24)
    - Looking up the Shenandoah [Shenandoah River (Va. and W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 24)
    - Bridge and "roaring canal," on the Shenandoah [Shenandoah River (Va. and W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 24)
    - Along the canal, on the Shenandoah [Shenandoah River (Va. and W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 24)
    - Methodist Church, Shenandoah Street [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 24)
    - Steps to the sanctuary, and to the upper town, from High Street [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 24)
    - High Street, looking down [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 24)
    - The Potomac, from the Episcopal Church [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 24)
    - Jefferson's Rock, above Harper's Ferry [Shenandoah River Valley (Va. and W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 24)
    - Street in the upper town [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 24)
    - The Potomac and canal, at Island Park Bridge [Potomac River], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 24)
    - Looking down the Potomac [Potomac River], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 24)
    - We, our private car and attendants [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 24)
    - Harper's Ferry from the B. & O. R. R. Station [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 24)
    - The river, railroad, and bridges [Potomac River], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 24)
    - After dinner group [Harper's Ferry (W. Va.)], 1900 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 24)
  - Subseries II.26: [No title] [Album 24], 26
    - [Bronx (New York, N.Y.)], 1913 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
      Same image as Alland # 1720A
    - [] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
      Same image as Alland # 1773A
    - Municipal Building - City Hall from Mail Street [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1913 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
      Same image as Alland # 1363
    - City Hall - Municipal Building - World Building [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1913 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
      Same image as Alland # 1369
    - [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1909 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
      Same image as Alland # 33
    - [] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
    - Battle lane from Fort Washington before 1912 [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
    - Fort Washington Park [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1914 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
    - American Redout, Fort Washington Park [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1914 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
    - Lane to the River [Fort Lee (N.J.)], 1914 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
    - [] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
    - House at Kimbel Point [] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
    - [], 1891 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
    - [] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
    - [] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
    - [] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
    - Neck Road, Gravesend, N.Y. from East 3rd Street [Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
    - Water fountain, Riverside Drive and 116th Street [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
    - [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
    - [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
    - Post Building - Singer Building [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
    - [] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
    - [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
    - [] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 29, Album 25)
  - Subseries II.27: [No title] [Album 26], 27
    - [Somerville (N.J.)] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 26)
      Same image as Alland # 888
    - [Somerville (N.J.)] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 26)
    - [Somerville (N.J.)] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 26)
    - [Somerville (N.J.)] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 26)
  - Subseries II.28: [No title] [Album 27], 28
    - [Yonkers (N.Y.)] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 27)
      Same image as Alland # 1774
    - [Yonkers (N.Y.)] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 27)
      Same image as Alland # 912
    - [] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 27)
      Same image as Alland # 1191
    - [] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 27)
      Same image as Alland # 28
    - [Tarrytown (N.Y.)] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 27)
    - [Tarrytown (N.Y.)] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 27)
    - [] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 27)
    - [] (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 27)
  - Subseries II.29: "War Bulletins" [Album 28], 29
    - Mail & Express Bulletin Board, 203 Broadway [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1898 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 28)
      Same image as Alland # 324A
    - Mail & Express Bulletin Board, 203 Broadway [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1898 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 28)
      Same image as Alland # 340C
    - Evening Post Bulletins, Broadway, cor. Fulton St. [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1898 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 28)
      Same image as Alland # 2157A
    - Evening Post Bulletins, Broadway, cor. Fulton St. [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1898 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 28)
      Same image as Alland # 2157
    - Commercial Advertiser, 29 Park Row, Patterson Bros. at 27 Park Row [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1898 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 28)
      Same image as Alland # 2170B
    - New York Press, Potter Building, Park Row, Beekman Street [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1898 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 28)
      Same image as Alland # 2170A
    - Printing House Square, Brooklyn Bridge Approach [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1898 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 28)
      Same image as Alland # 2199
    - New York Journal, New York Tribune, Park Row [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1898 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 28)
      Same image as Alland # 324
    - Benjamin Franklin Statue, Printing House Square [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1898 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 28)
      Same image as Alland # 2170
    - Benjamin Franklin Statue, Printing House Square [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1898 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 28)
      Same image as Alland # 340
    - Benjamin Franklin Statue, Printing House Square [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1898 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 28)
      Same image as Alland # 340B
    - New York World, Perry's Pharmacy [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1898 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 28)
      Same image as Alland # 340A
    - Looking down Nassau Street [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1898 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 28)
      Same image as Alland # 325
    - Post Office, Broadway - Park Row [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1898 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 28)
    - Newsboys [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1898 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 28)
    - Newsboys [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1898 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 28)
    - Looking across City Hall Park to Times Building [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1898 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 28)
    - City Hall Park from corner of Broadway & Park Place [Manhattan (New York, N.Y.)], 1898 (Offsite-box 23-30, Box 30, Album 28)
- Series III: Trappan Gift: Other Materials
  - Subseries III.1: Trappan Gift: Documentary Material
    This subseries incorporates ephemera belonging to Bracklow and material related to Bracklow accumulated by Ruth Trappan. Bracklow material includes unused boards for a planned Marblehead album, Bracklow's notes of titles in negative boxes (these are loose, as compared to those laid in to the 1903 datebook in Subseries III.2), a map of Long Island, a postcard of Marblehead, MA, and several envelopes with Bracklow's stamp on them. Other material consists of a folder of 7 pictures and cabinet cards of Mary Granger (two are taken by Bracklow), Ruth Trappan's copy of Mary Black's Old New York in Early Photographs 1853-1901 (New York: Dover, 1973), and typed captions describing Bracklow photos from a planned exhibit by Ruth Trappan.
    - Bracklow's negative box notes, Undated (Offsite-box 31, Box 31, Folder 111)
    - Envelopes, postcards, etc., Undated (Offsite-box 31, Box 31, Folder 112)
    - Photos of Mary Granger, 1897, undated (Offsite-box 31, Box 31, Folder 113)
    - Trappan's photo captions, Undated (Offsite-box 31, Box 31, Folder 114)
    - Trappan's copy of Old New York in Early Photographs, 1973 (Offsite-box 31, Box 31, Folder 115)
  - Subseries III.2: Trappan Gift: Logbooks
    This subseries includes two logbooks, one kept by Bracklow and one created by John Judson Trappan, Ruth Trappan's father. The Bracklow logbook is a commercially published datebook for 1903 (perhaps of a kind sold by Bracklow in his stationery store) in which he has recorded the titles of negatives in a number of negative boxes. Bracklow ignored the datebook's printed dates and instead wrote about eight titles per page. This book also contains several loose pieces of paper, which seem to have once accompanied negative boxes, on which photograph titles are also recorded. The other logbook is a composition book in which John Trappan recorded the subjects of the photographs in Bracklow's albums. A photograph of Bracklow is pasted to the front. It is unclear why Trappan undertook this project, but the book, which is in good condition, provides a quick reference to the albums.
    - 1903 Datebook, 1903, Undated (Offsite-box 31, Box 31, Folder 116)
    - Logbook of prints in albums, Undated (Offsite-box 31, Box 31, Folder 117)
  - Subseries III.3: Trappan Gift: Vintage Prints
    Some of these prints have Bracklow's notation along the bottom. Most are undated. Trappan grouped the photos by city or state, and this arrangement has been kept as much as possible. Trappan also wrote on the back of some of these prints, and in this case signed her notations "R.T." Many of these scenes are from the same trips documented in the photo albums, such as Fort Lee and Somerset, N.J., and New Rochelle, N.Y. Others are from towns either not well represented, or otherwise unrepresented, in the albums and Alland's prints, such as Bridgehampton, N.Y., Sag Harbor, N.Y., and Boston, MA. Three of these prints are cyanotypes. Several landscapes, of an unidentified location, show intense light contrast. The two still lifes in this subseries (in box 33, under the heading "Other") appear to be the only studio shots in the collection. Prints are organized by size, by state and city, when known, and then by subject.
    - 7 x 9" prints (7), 1901, Undated (Offsite-box 31, Folder 118)
    - 5 x 7" prints--Connecticut--Clinton, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--Connecticut--New London, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--Connecticut--New Milford, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--Connecticut--Miscellaneous, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--Maine, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--Massachusetts--Boston, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--Massachusetts--Great Barrington, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--Massachusetts--Lenox, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--Massachusetts--Lexington, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--Massachusetts--Marblehead, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--Massachusetts--Medford, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--Massachusetts--Newburyport, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--Massachusetts--Stockbridge, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--Massachusetts--Miscellaneous, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--New Hampshire, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--New Jersey--Hackensack, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--New Jersey--Jersey City, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--New Jersey--Morristown, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--New Jersey--Somerville, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--New Jersey--Miscellaneous, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--New York--Bridgehampton, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--New York--East Hampton, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--New York--Hudson River, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--New York--New Rochelle, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--New York--New York City, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--New York--Sag Harbor, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--New York--Miscellaneous, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--Pennsylvania, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--Rhode Island, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--Virginia, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints--Unidentified location--Bridges, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints---Unidentified location--Buildings, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints---Unidentified location--Churches, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints---Unidentified location--Houses, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints---Unidentified location--Landscapes, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints---Unidentified location--Other, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints---Unidentified location--Rivers, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints---Unidentified location--Streets, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints---Unidentified location--Waterfronts, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
    - 5 x 7" prints---Unidentified location--Views, Undated (Offsite-box 32, Box 32)
  - Subseries III.4: Trappan Gift: Lantern Slides
    - 8 Lantern Slides, Undated (Offsite-box 33)
      The 7 slides in this subseries include several portraits of Bracklow, including one shot of him and a friend in a cow yoke. A modern copy print was made of this image for the 1983 exhibit, and can be found in the collection file. Other slides show Bracklow's friend Moses Joy, Grace Church, and Fulton market.
- Series IV: Other Sources
  This series is made up of the small amount of Bracklow material acquired from other sources.
  - 1949 Gift, Undated (Offsite-box 33, Box 33, Folder 119)
    Mrs. Hopper Striker Mott donated one "Glimpses Through the Camera" mounted photo.
  - 1983 Gift, 1900 (Offsite-box 34, Box 34, Folder 120)
    Alfred Lowenherz gave the N-YHS a photograph of a Camera Club party ca. 1900. Bracklow is pictured at the far right. Lowenherz made the print from an original photograph either for, or because of, the 1983 Bracklow exhibit.
  - 1984 Purchase, 1888 Apr.-1892 Oct. (Offsite-box 34, Box 34, Folder 121)
    N-YHS purchased 8 "Glimpses Through the Camera" mounted photographs. These images show New York scenes: Washington Bridge, Rose Street, Brighton Beach Hotel, two children in front of the first City Hall site in New York, the Herald Building, the Pedestal for the Columbus Statue in Columbus Circle, Park Row with newspaper buildings, and Murray Street. Bracklow's interest in the changing cityscape can be scene in his captions for these photos. He notes that the Herald Building is "now torn down," and the buildings shown on Murray Street are about to be torn down.
  - 1992 Gift, 1890-91, undated (Offsite-box 34, Box 34, Folder 122)
    Dealer Charles Schwartz donated 14 of the "Glimpses Through the Camera" mounted photographs. At the time of the donation N-YHS chose images which were not otherwise represented in the Collection. Most of these views lack either Bracklow's stamp on the back, captions for the photographs, or both. Two identified photographs depict Fourth Avenue Presbyterian Church and Bloomingdale Reformed Church. Unidentified images show men with cattle, the First Methodist Church on John Street, churches, country houses or hotels, a pier, and rocks along the ocean.
  - 2002 Gift, 1892, undated (Offsite-box 34, Box 34, Folder 123)
    Charles Schwartz gave two more "Glimpses Through the Camera" photographs in 2002. One of these shows St. Paul's Chapel at Broadway and Fulton Streets. The other image is of the corner of Broadway and Murray Street in March 1892.